<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="000style.xsl"?>
<teiCorpus>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digitised and Encoded copy of Negro Slavery by Zachary MacAulay</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Transcribed from digital copy available from Recovered Histories at
                    http://www.recoveredhistories.org/pamphlet1.php?page=1&amp;orderby=MaxID&amp;catid=66</authority>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Negro Slavery; or, A View of Some of the More Prominent Features of
                            that State of Society, as it Exists in the United States of America and
                            in the Colonies of the West Indies, Especially in Jamaica</title>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Printed for Hatchard and Son, Piccadilly, and J. and A. Arch,
                            Cornhill</publisher>
                        <distributor>Sold Also by W. Graphel, Church street, and G. and J. Robison,
                            Castle Street, Liverpool.</distributor>
                        <date when="1823">1823</date>
                        <pubPlace>
                            <settlement>London</settlement>
                        </pubPlace>
                    </publicationStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <TEI>
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title/>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Transcribed by a student of Digital History at Carleton
                        University</authority>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <bibl>
                        <biblScope>52</biblScope>
                    </bibl>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
                <p>But it may be asked whether no time, except Sunday, is given to the slaves for
                the raising of food. The law of the island requires that one day in a fortnight,
                except during the time of crop, should be allowed to the slaves, exclusive of
                Sunday, cultivating their provision-grounds. This would amount to from fourteen to
                sixteen days in the year, The proprietor of <placeName key="Hanover, Jamaica"
                ref="https://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?params=18_25_1_N_78_7_58_W">Georgia</placeName>
                was, however, more liberal than the law. There the slaves were allowed for this purpose
                (and other proprietors in that quarter,<persName key="Cooper, Thomas" from="?" to="?" role="Pastor"
                >Mr. Cooper</persName> thinks, may have been equally liberal, every Saturday after crop,
                until they began to dig the land into holes for the fall-plant, when they are allowed only
                every second Saturday. By this arrangement, the Negroes belonging to Georgia had about
                twenty-eight days in the year allowed them for the cultivation of their grounds, besides Sundays.</p>
                <p>As this time, however, had been given them for the express purpose of raising
                their food, it would have been unjust to the slaves, and would have placed both
                religion and its minister in an odious light, had any part of it been authoritatively
                diverted from its original destination, with a view to attendance upon <persName key="Cooper, Thomas"
                from="?" to="?" role="Pastor">him</persName>. Accordingly it was agreed that, out of crop,
                an afternoon every fortnight should be allowed for religious service and instruction.
                Mr. Cooper had thus an opportunity of preaching to the slaves about eleven or twelve times
                in the year. But the moment crop began, there was an entire cessation for five or six months
                of all meetings of the kind.</p>
                <p>After remaining in this unsatisfactory state for upwards of three years,Mr. Cooper
                as has been already remarked, quitted Jamaica and returned to Great Britain. He justly
                observes, that it could perhaps hardly</p>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
</teiCorpus>
